A Guide to the Robert W. Williams Papers, 1880-1995
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert W. Williams Papers, 1880-1995
The Library of Virginia
45531
9 cubic feet (20 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mike and Susie Cluff, Alexandria.
Biographical Information
Robert Wesley Williams was born in Minneapolis, Minnesota on 25 July 1911. He was the son of Dr. Robert Williams (1875-1962) and Martha Golden Davidson (1876-1936). He graduated from Carlton College in Northfield, Minnesota, the moved to Washington, DC, where he was employed as a fingerprint examiner with the Federal Bureau of Investigation. Williams later worked for the Social Security Board, Railroad Retirement Board, War Department, Veterans Adminstration, and the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare. He married Dorothy Joyce Hudgens (1912-2008) on 30 December 1939 in Mobile, Alabama. They resided in Alexandria, Virginia. Robert W. Williams died on 15 January 1997.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1880-1995, of Robert W. Williams (1911-1995) of Alexandria, Virginia, including his genealogical research and family papers. The majority of the collection consists of his revisions to a genealogy of the descendants of Thomas Gillham, Sr. (ca. 1740-1790) of Augusta County, Virginia and Union County, South Carolina, compiled by W. Clark Gillham (1894-1980). Williams also compiled a genealogy of the descendants of William D. Hudgens (1784-1849) of McMinn County, Tennessee, Washington County, Kentucky, and Phelps County, Missouri. He also researched the family of John Ownby II (1781-1869) of Buncombe and Rutherford Counties, North Carolina. There are transcriptions of cemetery and census records, correspondence with family and other researchers, drafts, family group sheets, genealogical charts and pedigrees, military and pension records, newsletters, obituaries, and copies of published sources. Other surnames include Campbell, Credo, Davidson, Light, Lusk, Springer, and Williams.
Other items of note in the collection include transcriptions of letters written by Wesley Cutler Williams (1833-1891), while he was serving with the 12 Illinois Cavalry during the Civil War, a large group of personal papers of Charles Adolph Schueller (1857-1937) of Brooklyn, New York, and personal correspondence of Williams and his wife Dorothy with members of the Hudgens family.
Contents List
- Avis. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bankhead. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Barney, Jacob (Salem, MA). (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bell-Hudgins. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bobbitt. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Boulden. (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- Brant, Rev. Gordon E. and Helen. (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Campbell. (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Campbell-Gillham-Davidson. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Descendants of Duncan Campbell and Mary McCoy" by J. Lyle Campbell. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Carroll County, IL. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Certificates. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Christmas Cards. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Civil War Letters - Transcriptions - Wesley C. Williams. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Clan Campbell Society. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Clan Davidson Society. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Clippings. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Davidson. (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
- Davidson. (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
- Davidson - Family Sheets - Incomplete Set. (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
- Davidson, James Bankhead. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Davidson, Richard T.. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Davidson, Vance. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Diary, 1971. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Dunnagan. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Estate of Charles A. Schueller. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Garrett. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Gillham. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Gillham - Civil War. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Gillham-Davidson. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Gillham - Family Sheets. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Gillham, Isaac. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Gillham, Jacob C.. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Gillham - Military. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "Gillham News". (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Gillham - Supplemental Data. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Gillham - War of 1812. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Goldwater. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Grace Episcopal Church (Alexandria, VA). (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Graham, A. Townsend (Hancock County, IL). (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Haige, Joyce (Ownbey Research). (Box 5, Folder 4)
- "The Hartwells of Canon City, Colorado" by Elizabeth Davidson Wheatley and Philip G. Davidson, Jr.. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Hatten, Ruth L.. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Holy Trinity (Old Swedes) Church. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Hudgens. (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
- Hudgens, Ambrose (Laurens County, SC). (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Hudgens Book No. 1 by J.J. Watts. (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
- Hudgens Cemetery Association. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Hudgens - Census. (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
- Hudgens - Charts. (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
- Hudgens, Dora. (Box 6, Folder 5a)
- Hudgens, Dorothy Joyce. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Hudgens, Edward D. - Correspondence, 1966-1969. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Hudgens Family Bible Records. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Hudgens Family History. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- "The Hudgens Family of Kentucky" by Deloris Shelton Best. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Hudgens Family Letters (Outgoing), 1965-1972. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Hudgens Family Letters, 1954-1993. (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
- Hudgens Family Letters, 1954-1993. (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
- Hudgens Family Letters, 1981-1984. (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
- Hudgens, Frances. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Hudgens Genealogy - First Draft. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Hudgens Genealogy - 1970 Draft. (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
- Hudgens Genealogy - 1970 Draft. (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Introduction. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 1. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 2. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 3. (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 4. (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 5. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 6. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapters 7, 10, 12. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 8. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 9. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Chapter 11. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Hudgens Genealogy - Index. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Hudgens, Gil. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- "Houlder Hudgins of Mathews County, Virginia and His Descendants" by Houlder Hudgins IV. (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Hudgens, Nola Owensby. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Hudgens, Robert - Charts. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Hudgens, Robert Luther. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Hudgens, Starling. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Hudgens, Tony A.. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Light. (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
- London. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Lusk. (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
- "Macoupin County Illinois Marriage Records Index, 1829-1838". (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Maps. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Mason. (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Mason-Scarritt. (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Military Service and Pension Records. (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Millwee. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Moore. (Box 10, Folder 5-9)
- Moravian Cemetery, New Dorp, Staten Island. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- "Nathaniel Morrison of Virginia and Some of His Descendants" by Arthur C. Morrison. (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Obituaries. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Ogle. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Ogle - Genealogical Charts. (Map-case 2, Drawer 12)
- Olsen, Addis G.. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Oneby - England. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Introduction. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 1. (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 2. (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 2. (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 5. (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 6. (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 7. (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 7. (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 8. (Box 13, Folder 4-9)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 9. (Box 13, Folder 10)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 10. (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
- "Our Gillham Family" - Section 11. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Owen. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Owens. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
- Owensby. (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
- Owensby, Arthur Dow. (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Owensby - Census. (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
- Owensby, James Coon. (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Owensby, Lorenzo Dow. (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
- Owensby, Lorenzo Dow. (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
- Owensby Proofs. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Ownbey, Arthur. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Ownbey, Nicholas. (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Ownbey, Peter. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Ownby. (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
- Ownby, Amos. (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Ownby - Civil War. (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Ownby Genealogy. (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Ownby - Heard County, GA. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Ownby, John Jr.. (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Ownby - Miscellaneous Notes. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Ownby, Nancy Ann (Hills). (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Ownby Notes. (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Ownby - Unknown. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Ownsby - Correspondence (A-K). (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Ownsby - Correspondence (L-Z). (Box 17, Folder 8)
- "The Phelps Countian". (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Photographs - Owensby, Mary Esther. (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Pocahontas. (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Reagan, Timothy (1750-1830). (Box 17, Folder 12)
- "Roster of Cemetery and Historical Sketch of Bullock Creek Church". (Box 17, Folder 13)
- "Rutherford County NC 1790 Census and 1782 Tax List". (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Sage. (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Scrapbook. (Box PP Oversize Box 59)
- "St. James - Forest City of the Ozarks" by Irene McManus. (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Scarritt. (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Schueller. (Box 18, Folder 1-10)
- Society of the War of 1812. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Sons of the American Revolution. (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Sons of Confederate Veterans. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Springer. (Box 19, Folder 4)
- "Charles Springer of Cranehook-on-the-Delaware". (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
- Springer, Rev. Elihu - Diary, 1840-1843 (Typed Transcription). (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Trotter. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Tucker. (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Tweed. (Box 19, Folder 10)
- University High School 50th Reunion, 1978. (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Usry, John M.. (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Williams. (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
- Williams, David S. and Irene - Correspondence, 1936-1938. (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Williams, Robert W. - Biographical Material. (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Williams, Robert W. - Correspondence, 1936-1937. (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Williams, Robert W. - Pedigree Chart. (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Winfrey-Butcher. (Box 20, Folder 11)